原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
《沼泽怪物》前情回顾
Previously on Swamp Thing...
这是用来兑现的
It's made out to cash.
你到底有什么目的  桑德兰  这样买一个孩子
So what's this really about, Sunderland? Buying a kid like this?
她在这里挺开心的
She seems happy here.
我只希望上帝保佑她平安
I just hope to God she's okay.
所以我才一直资助伍德罗博士
That's why I'm keeping Dr. Woodrue on the payroll.
这些数字
These numbers.
它们只适用于表示细胞壁的厚度
They can only refer to the thickness of a cell wall.
所以要么是植物
So it's either a plant,
要么是动物
or an animal.
如果我说输入的数字是准确的呢
And what if I told you my entries are accurate?
过去一千万年的生物学不会同意
Well, the last ten million years of biology would disagree with you.
我也不会
As would I.
-你好  戈登  -无可奉告
- Hello, Gordon. - Got nothing to say.
我知道你一直在秘密贷款
I know you've been making off-the-books loans
给埃弗里·桑德兰
to Avery Sutherland.
我要查的人是他
It's him I want.
你有看见其它什么吗
Have you seen anything more?
有关我的使命的信息
About my... mission?
卡牌并不明朗
The cards aren't clear.
不只是你
Not just about you.
整个镇子的未来都不明朗
About the future of this entire town.
我好像找到那场爆炸的残骸了
I think I found some debris from the explosion.
这是霍兰船上的
This is from Holland's boat.
看起来有人开枪打了他
Looks like someone shot him.
我为你担心  艾比
I'm scared for you, Abby.
一切才刚刚开始
This is only the beginning.
苏西睡下了
Susie's in bed now.
说实话  我以为她会需要
To be honest, I thought it would take her
更长的时间来适应
a little bit longer to acclimate,
毕竟她经历了那么多
after everything she's been through.
但她似乎很喜欢这里
But she seems to like it here.
你什么时候回家
What time will you be back?
我明天一大早就开会
Well, meeting's first thing in the morning,
所以应该不会太晚
so I shouldn't be too late.
玛丽亚
Maria?
你在听吗
You there?
抱歉  我想她可能醒了
Sorry. I... I think that she might be awake.
听着  埃弗里  谢谢你安排这一切
Listen, thanks, Avery, for arranging all of this.
要知道  应该是我感谢你
Well, you know, it's me that should be thanking you.
感谢什么
What for?
感谢你资助伍德罗博士的研究
For funding Dr. Woodrue's research, you know.
有了你的帮助  他就能保持小苏西的健康
With your help, he's gonna be able to keep little Susie healthy,
还有其他很多人的健康
and a lot of other people, too.
我最好去看看她  好吗
I better go check on her, okay?
好  最好去看看  亲爱的  明天见
Okay, yeah, you better, hon. I'll see you tomorrow.
莉兹·崔梅恩
把该死的电话挂了  给我滚过来
Put that damn thing out and get your ass over here.
遵命  警长
Yes, ma'am, Sheriff.
苏西
Susie!
Susie?
苏西
Susie.
怎么了  亲爱的  出什么事了
What's wrong, honey? What happened?
刚刚有人站在那里
There was someone standing there.
-她看起来很愤怒  -谁
- She looked angry. - Who?
楼下照片里的那个女孩
The girl from the pictures downstairs.
你只是做噩梦了
You just had a nightmare.
这完全正常  新房子  新床
It's perfectly normal, new house, new bed.
你身上好凉
You're so cold.
我去给你拿条暖和点的毯子
I'll get you a warmer blanket.
不不不  求你了
No, no, no. Please.
求你别走
Please don't go.
就在走廊的壁橱里  好吗
It's just in the hall closet, okay?
我马上就回来
I'll be right back.
你知道吗  我小时候也会做噩梦
You know, I used to have nightmares when I was a little girl.
我妈妈总是会给我盖上暖和的毯子
And my mom would always bring me a warm blanket
然后一切都好了
and make it all better.
苏西
Susie.
苏西  你去哪了
Susie, where did you go?
苏西
Susie.
Susie!
肖娜  肖娜
Shawna! Shawna.
肖娜
Shawna!
天啊  肖娜
Oh, God. Shawna.
肖娜
Shawna!
你想要替代掉我
You tried to replace me.
先是用艾比  现在是用她
First with Abby, and now with her.
不是的  我...
No, I...
我从没那么想过
I never wanted that.
我只有你
It was only you.
肖娜  我对你的爱永无止境
Shawna, I love you more than you'll ever know.
翻译  布塔
翻译  DustD
翻译  冰岛豆腐
翻译  石墨希
翻译  SwampSide152
翻译  DerbyNinja
翻译  余欢
翻译  马丁马丁回音山
翻译  沼泽小鱼人
翻译  iLOST
翻译  管家大愚
时间轴  紫夏
时间轴  西·查
校对  屯栗子想变形
校对  布塔
后期  渔夫
字幕总监制  布塔
沼泽   怪物
第一季  第五集
以后用来做参考  黄色标记意思是
Just for future reference, yellow tag means
"诱变活性最强的区域"
"Especially active mutagenic site."
提醒自己  每周回来检查
Note to self. Check back every week
评估这个地区的植物疯狂生长的状态
to assess the insane plant growth in this area.
嗯
Yeah.
这非常好
Yeah, this is good.
我不知道这里发生了什么
I don't know what's happening out here,
但是这对我的事业有好处
but this is gonna be good for my career,
我想  也许能让我的生活回归正轨
I think, and could get my life back on track.
求好运  有事要发生了
Knock on wood. Something's coming.
是好事
Something good.
一切都将改变
Everything's about to change.
我是怎么了
What's happening to me?
不
No.
住手  我不想看这些
Stop it. I don't want to see this.
停下来
Make it stop!
这边钓鱼怎么样
How's the fishing around here?
镇上的伙计都说
'Cause the folks in town
鲈鱼会直接跳上你的船
said the bass would jump right up in your boat.
你应该离开
You should leave now.
这里不安全
It's not safe here.
我喜欢这里  真的
I love it out here. I really do.
潮湿的味道
The sweaty smells,
茂盛的草  那些花
the funky grass, the blossoms.
那些树
The trees.
我发誓  当风向正当好的时候
I swear, when the wind's just right,
你可以听到它们在细语秘密
you can hear 'em whispering their secrets.
那些树
The trees...
你可以从那后边出来
You can come on out of there if you want.
鱼在咬钩  我不咬人
The fish are biting, not me.
来吧
Come on.
你不害怕我
You're not afraid of me.
我应该害怕你吗
Are you someone I should be afraid of?
不是害怕之前的我
Not of who I was.
而是现在我变成的样子
Of what I've become.
生命中的改变
Transitions in life.
可能非常艰辛
They can be difficult.
毛毛虫到蝴蝶
Caterpillar to butterfly,
儿童到大人  生命的进程
child to adult... The process in life, it's, uh,
从来都不简单
it's never easy.
但这里的东西
But what's in here?
除了你没人能够夺走
Nobody can take that away except for you.
你是谁
Who are you?
蓝魔鬼音像店
上吧  上吧
Do it. Do it.
离开玛雷
靠
Shit!
离开玛雷
好了
All right.
我信守了承诺
I lived up to my end of the bargain.
我现在可以离开了吧
I can leave now, right?
救命
Help!
我被安插在这是为了等艾比·亚凯恩  对吗
I was planted here to wait for Abby Arcane, right?
她已经来了
Well, she's here.
还有
And by the way,
我救了她一命
I saved her neck.
但是我不仅
But instead of getting a
不能回好莱坞
gold star from my ride back to Hollywood,
反而又遭遇这个
I get this again?
我只想休息一下
I just wanted a break.
要是知道我会被困在这鬼地方
If I had known I'd be trapped in this hell,
我绝不会做交易...见鬼
I never would have made that... Argh! Shit.
扮演你显然不值得做这么大牺牲
Playing you definitely was not worth all this.
等我回洛杉矶后
When I get back to LA,
我就卖了你
I'm selling your ass.
刚才
That was a...
你怎么了
What's gotten into you?
我不知道
I don't know.
在那晚的事之后  我想
After whatever it was that happened the other night, I guess...
我想这正是我所需要的
I guess I just needed that.
不管你怎么了
But whatever it was that got into you,
我希望能更频繁
I hope it gets into you more often.
你去哪儿
Where you going?
-得了吧  埃弗里  -你干什么
- Come on, Avery. - What are you doing?
你这就走了
What, that's it?
中午才退房呢
I got the room till noon.
嗯
Well...
我们都清楚  最好的做法就是
We both know that this works best when...
保持短暂与美好
we just keep it short and sweet.
有些线我们最好不要跨越
You know, there's some lines that we're better off not crossing.
你总是戴着那戒指  对吗
You always wear that ring, don't you?
不是总是
Not always.
我记得我给你的那天
I remember the day I gave it to you.
或许是我这辈子最开心的一天
It might be my favorite day I ever had.
那是很久以前了
It was a long time ago.
你有想过要是我们在一起会怎么样吗
You ever think about what might have been?
你是说在玛丽亚带着微笑和无尽的金钱
You mean before Maria sashayed into town
来到这里之前
with her smiles and the bottomless bank account?
我以为玛丽亚
Thought that Maria was one of those lines
就是你不该跨越的线之一
you're not supposed to cross.
别担心  埃弗里  发号施令的还是你
Well, don't you worry, Avery. You're still calling the shots.
一向如此
Just like you always have.
该死
Shit.
莉兹·崔梅恩
Liz Tremayne.
她昨晚给我留了三条语音信息
She already left me three messages last night.
是吗
Really?
找你什么事
What's that all about?
她在打听她女友在蚊子湾
She's asking about some evidence her girlfriend
找到的证据
found up in Skeeter Cove.
铝船的残骸上有爆破痕迹
A piece of aluminum skiff with blast marks
和铅弹弹孔
and buckshot holes.
有人想置霍兰于死地的证据
Proof that someone wanted Holland dead.
她在催促警方展开调查
She's pushing for an investigation.
你怎么看
Well, what do you think?
我觉得可以写一篇很棒的报道
I think it would make for great copy in the weekly.
这些该死的记者  他们一嗅到水里有血...
Damn reporters. Once they smell blood in the water...
但我还是得去查查
Yeah. Still, I gotta look into it.
得赶在崔梅恩之前
Gotta solve this so-called murder
破了这所谓的凶杀案
before Tremayne beats me to it.
这个样本跟我此前见过的都完全不一样
This sample is unlike anything I've ever seen before.
这些细胞似乎在
The cells are expanding and contracting
随意伸缩
seemingly at will.
细胞死亡之后  又会再生
If destroyed, they regenerate,
完全不符合生物学常理
defying all laws of biology as we know it.
真不敢相信我会这么说
I can't believe I'm going to say this,
但根据我这几天所观察到的
but based on what I've seen in the past few days,
我开始思索
I'm beginning to wonder
我们所面对的
if we're dealing with
也许是当今科学无法解释的...
something beyond the known scope of science--
例如呢
Like what?
举个例子
For instance.
天啊
Jesus.
你从来不敲门的吗
Do you ever knock?
我获准使用医院设施的时候
I was told I had free rein
他们告诉我可以自由出入
when I was provided hospital privileges.
非常明智  因为我们来自疾控中心的常驻专家
Wise decision, since our resident CDC professional appears to be
似乎要把这份独特的植物标本
attributing the characteristics of a unique plant specimen
妖魔化了
to the boogeyman.
医生
Doctor.
你之前给我看的那份植物样本
The plant sample you showed me earlier, I, uh...
我需要知道它是从哪来的
I need to know where it came from.
恐怕现在这是疾控中心的专业事务了
I'm afraid that's a CDC professional matter now.
那些细胞所具备的再生能力
Regenerative powers within those cells
将会革新
would revolutionize treatment
众多遗传病的治疗方式
for a host of genetic diseases.
是的
Yes.
而你难道不想看到自己的名字
And wouldn't you like to see your name
出现在宣布这一发现的期刊论文上吗
on top of the journal article announcing that discovery.
亚凯恩医生
Dr. Arcane,
你的发现跟亚历克·霍兰有关联吗
did your discovery have anything to do with Alec Holland?
你为什么会这么想
What... What makes you think that?
霍兰是这个小地方的唯一一位
Holland was the only scientist...
科学家  我再三考虑
And I use that word advisedly,
才称他为科学家
in this backwater.
他在沼泽里有间实验室
He had that lab back in the swamp.
他在工作过程中
It seems reasonable
非常有可能
that during the course of his work,
发现了你的这些样本
he may have come across your material.
那么  我猜得对吗
So, um, does it?
这些样本是不是跟亚历克·霍兰有关
Have anything to do with Alec Holland?
你知道吗  我得接这个电话
You know what? I have to take this.
先走一步  伍德罗博士
Excuse me, Dr. Woodrue.
苏西
Susie?
不  没关系  我马上过去
No, no. It's okay, I'll be right there.
早上好  戴尔瑞
Good morning, Delroy.
埃弗里先生
Mr. Avery?
你起得可真早
You're up early.
我今天早上醒来  突然特别想吃
Yeah, I woke up this morning with a powerful hunger
龟汤
for turtle soup.
我就自作主张
I took the liberty
用我的钥匙
of using my key
进你的厨房开工了
to help myself to your kitchen.
虽说实际上
Although technically,
这是我的厨房  因为这是我的房产
I guess it's my kitchen, 'cause I do own the property.
你来这里就是为了做汤吗
You came all this way for soup?
其实呢  戴尔瑞
Well, actually, Delroy,
我是来看你的
I wanted to see you.
你比任何人都清楚
You know better than anyone
我为这个小镇
how hard I've worked my ass off
付出了多少努力
for this town, you know?
我知道大家很感激你的付出
I know folks appreciate that.
真的吗  因为有时候我会想...
Do they? Because sometimes, I wonder, you know...
好像每次就在我快要追到
Seemed like every time I'm just about to land
出自美国小说《白鲸》  指求而不得
那条大白鲸的时候
that big white whale,
总是有人想让我功败垂成
there's somebody trying to tear me down.
以你女儿丽兹为例
Take your daughter Liz, for instance.
出于某些原因
Now, for some reason,
她不顾一切地
she is hell-bent
想要挖出我的黑幕
on digging up dirt about me.
提醒你一下  她什么都不会找到的
Mind you, there's nothing for her to find,
我只是需要她放松点
I just need her to ease up a little bit. You know,
当然是为了镇子好
for the good of the town, of course.
我希望你能够
And I was hoping that you could maybe
和她谈谈
talk to her
把我们讨论的转告她
and pass on what we discussed.
用你自己的话告诉她  戴尔瑞
In your own words, Delroy.
尝尝
Taste.
还是算了吧
I'd just as soon not.
尝尝
Taste.
你自己尝吧  桑德兰
Taste it yourself, Sunderland.
老爸  承包商在外面等着和你谈修理的事
Pops, the contractor's outside to talk about the repairs.
去吧  我不会有事的
Go ahead. I'll be fine.
我就在外面
I'll be right outside.
早上好  莉兹  要来点龟汤吗
Good morning, Liz. Would you like some turtle soup?
你觉得威吓我爸爸就能让我闭嘴吗
You think bullying my father's gonna shut me up?
我肯定是触及你的根本了
Must be hitting pretty close to the bone.
拜托  莉兹
Oh, come on now, Liz.
别这样
Let's not do this.
你还是小宝宝的时候我就认识你了
I've known you since you were a little baby.
你的银行家在哪儿  桑德兰
Where's your banker, Sunderland?
我的银行家
My banker?
我想想
Let me see.
我想他累坏了
Well, I think that man was exhausted.
他应该是去度假了  他告诉我的
And I believe he went on a vacation. That's what I was told.
那天晚上他本来要跟我谈他借给
The same night he was gonna talk to me about
桑德兰公司的违规贷款  却突然去度假了
some bullshit loans he made to the Sunderland Corporation?
就在亚历克·霍兰被烧死的几天后
A few days after Alec Holland went up in flames.
你把这些都想通了  是吗
You've got this all figured out, don't you?
我来问问你  孩子
Let me ask you something, girl.
如果我真的能够做到
If I was really capable of doing the things
你认为我已经做过的事
that you imagine that I've done,
你觉得我会让一个废物酒保挡我的路吗
do you really think I'd let a piece of bar trash get in my way?
你有什么证据  一艘报废的船
What do you got? You got a piece of a shot-up boat.
一个去度假的银行家
You got a banker that went on vacation.
你还有什么
What else you got?
我想应该没有了
I think that might be it.
所以帮你自己  你父亲
So do yourself, your old man,
还有这个镇子一个忙
and this whole town a favor.
别再纠缠我了
You leave me alone.
也许以前在这个镇子上
Might have been a time in this town
桑德兰家的人一打响指  人们便会一跃而起
when a Sunderland snapped his fingers and folks jumped.
但那个时代已经过去了
But that time has passed.
离我爸远点
Stay the hell away from my dad.
好好享用龟汤  莉兹
You enjoy that soup, Liz.
老埃弗里大概在七年前修建了这个地方
Ol' Avery built this here place maybe like seven years ago.
从很久以前起  他就一直
That boy has been screwing around these waters
在这片沼泽里折腾
for long as anyone can remember.
你确定亚历克·霍兰就是在这里进行研究的吗
You're certain this is where Alec Holland did his research?
是的  先生
Yes, sir.
几个月前给他送过一批设备
Delivered some equipment to him a few months back
那时候他刚开始准备
when he was just getting set up.
也许你还应该给他送一个监管人过来
Perhaps you should have delivered him a custodian as well.
看起来有什么可怕的生物破门而入了
Looks like something nasty busted up through the hatch.
弄得这里一片狼藉
Tore this place up good.
那生物肯定很大
Must've been big.
你在那看什么呢  博士
What are you rolling around there, Doc?
有可能
It's possible
我的想法太局限了
that I've been thinking too small.
你为什么带我来这里
Why have you brought me here?
你确定是我吗
You sure it was me?
也许召唤你的是这个地方
Maybe it was this place that called you.
你是什么人
Who are you?
只是个路过的陌生人
Just a passing stranger.
也许是梦里的幽灵
Maybe a phantom from a dream
想要帮助你理解一些你已经知道的事
trying to help you understand the things you already know.
这种老柏树
You know, some of these old cypress
有的可以活一千年
can live to be a thousand years old.
你能想象它们所见证过的事吗
Can you imagine the things that they've seen in their time?
你也在这看到了一些事对吧
You've seen some things out here, too, haven't you?
我看到了鬼魂
I've seen ghosts.
也可以这么想吧
That's one way to think of it.
也许还有另一种看待方式
Perhaps there's another way.
记忆
Memories
储存在树木中
held by the trees.
而万物之绿
And the green
将它们联系在一起
that connects them all together.
万物之绿
The green?
你目睹的
What you're seeing
是这些树木几个世纪以来所见证的记忆
are memories of events that they've witnessed over the centuries.
如果你听得够仔细
You listen close enough,
它们会给你讲述难以置信的故事
they'll tell you stories you won't even believe.
但是为什么
But why?
向我展示这些死亡的目的是什么
What is the purpose of showing me all of this death?
它们在警告你
They're warning you.
这里对一个
There's danger here...
你认识的人来说有危险
for someone you know.
来自过去的危险
A danger from the past,
即将回归
returning.
肖娜
Shawna!
肖娜  肖娜
Shawna! Shawna!
-艾比  -肖娜
- Abby! - Shawna!
玛丽亚
Maria.
我不想和你吵  但我必须来
I don't... I don't want to fight. I had to come.
她给你打电话了是吗
She called you, didn't she?
我求她别打  但是...
I begged her not to, but...
你知道她一旦下定决心  就不听别人的
You know how she gets when her mind's set.
我无法拒绝她
I could never deny her.
我很快就结束
I'll make this quick.
我只是想确保她没事
I just wanna make sure she's okay.
她没事
She's fine.
那个女孩真是这个家的福气
That girl has been a real blessing for this house.
也是我的福气
And for me.
你能听到她哼歌吗
Can you hear her?
就像是天使
It's just like an angel.
你疯了吗  你为什么这么做
Are you crazy? Why did you do that?
这是史密斯街大桥  你知道这意味着什么
It's Smith Street Bridge. You know what that means.
也有"狂欢派对"的意思
去吧
Go on.
她在等你
She's waiting for you.
苏西
Hey, Susie.
艾比  你真的来了
Abby. You actually came.
我很惊讶
I'm surprised.
为什么
Why?
因为在大家真的需要你时
Because when people really need you,
你从来不会出现
you're never there.
你这么想我很遗憾
I'm sorry you feel that way.
你介意我快速检查一下
Do you mind if I do a quick exam
确保你没事吗
and make sure everything's all right?
差点忘了
Almost forgot.
你现在是大医生了
You're a big-time doctor now.
看着我
Look at me.
你认为我嗑药了吗
Do you think I'm on something?
你知道我不嗑药的
You know I don't take drugs.
我只是检查一下  亲爱的
I know, I'm just checking, honey.
看起来一切正常
Everything looks great.
你刚刚哼的那首歌
That song you were humming,
-你从哪听来的  -和你一起听的
- where did you hear it? - With you.
你不记得了吗
Don't you remember?
是我们最爱的歌
It was our favorite.
摇下车窗
Windows down,
微风掠过我们的头发  大声播放电台
breeze in our hair, blasting the radio?
好吧
Okay.
吸气
Breathe in for me.
很好
Good.
呼气
Exhale for me.
呼气  苏西
Breathe out, Susie.
苏西
Susie.
Susie!
你应该看看自己的表情  比艾
You should see your face, Y-Bee.
你刚叫我什么
What did you just call me?
不是吧
Seriously?
那是你倒念的名字
That's your reverse name.
-你是比艾  我是...  -娜肖
- You were Y-Bee, and I was-- - A-Shawn.
苏西
Susie,
是桑德兰夫人让你这样做的吗
did Mrs. Sunderland put you up to this?
苏西已经不在了
Susie's not here anymore.
我不会允许妈妈用这个小不点取代我的
I won't let Mom replace me with this little nothing.
好吧  好吧
Okay. Okay.
说服我
Convince me.
如果你是肖娜  告诉我你为什么在这
If you're Shawna, tell me why you're here.
救救我  艾比  救救我
Save me, Abby. Save me.
你想要从我这得到什么
What do you want from me?
想看你在那片沼泽里
To see you in that swamp,
在肮脏的水里
in that filthy water.
慢慢死去  挣扎着想要呼吸
Dying, gasping for air,
就像你离我而去  我那样挣扎一样
just the way that you left me.
你不是肖娜  肖娜已经死了
You're not Shawna. Shawna's dead.
因你而死
'Cause of you.
你到底对她做了什么
What the hell did you do to her?
你说什么
Excuse me?
你是不是给她灌输了肖娜的事情
Have you been filling her head with stories of Shawna?
否则她不可能知道我们的昵称
It's the only way she could have known our nicknames,
-我们的歌...  -我什么都没跟她说
- our song... - I didn't tell her anything.
她自己知道的
She knew.
上都把我的肖娜带回来了
Xanadu brought my Shawna back to me.
上都夫人
Madame Xanadu?
你去找她了
You went to her?
她警告过我要注意你
She warned me about you.
她跟我说过你会想要让我相信
She told me that you were gonna try and convince me
肖娜不是真的回来了
that Shawna wasn't really here.
说你会再把她从我身边夺走
That you were gonna try and take her away from me again.
你以为我想要肖娜死吗
You think I wanted Shawna to die?
你那么恨我吗
You hate me that much?
出去
Get out.
滚出去  不然我就报警了
Get out of here before I call the police.
妈妈
Mom?
肖娜  肖娜
Shawna. Shawna.
都会没事的
Everything's gonna be okay.
都会过去的
Everything's gonna be all right.
我向你保证
I promise.
我无法一直维持下去  你知道的
I can't stay like this forever, you know.
很快  我就得离开苏西了
Soon, I'll have to let Susie go.
沼泽在召唤我回去
The water's calling me back.
不  亲爱的  我不能再失去你一次了  肖娜
No, honey. I can't lose you again, Shawna.
我不能再孤身一人了
I can't be alone anymore.
跟我一起去沼泽吧  妈妈
Come with me to the swamp, Mom,
那样我们就能在一起了
and we can be together.
永远在一起
Forever.
儿童服务部  请留言
Department of Child Services. Leave me a message.
我是艾比·亚凯恩
It's Abby Arcane.
有时间请尽快给我回电
Give me a call as soon as you get a second.
有些状况我们急需讨论一下
There's a situation we need to discuss.
艾比盖尔
Abigail.
肖娜回来了  是不是
Shawna's come back, hasn't she?
玛丽亚最近照看的那个女孩
The little girl Maria's been watching,
她有危险了
she's in danger.
我准备在雷米·德博阿的小屋外停车了
I'm about to pull up outside Remy Dubois' shack.
鼠男吗
Rat boy?
港务长说霍兰被杀当晚
Harbormaster said he was actually working the dock
是他在码头值班
the night of the Holland murder.
觉得他可能看见了什么
Thought he might have seen something.
收到
Copy that.
要我派马特去你那边吗
Should I send Matt out your way?
不用了  我回警局再跟他碰头
Negative. I'll meet him back at the station.
这不会花太久
This won't take long.
闻着不错
Smells good.
我就猜到你会来
Thought you might be coming around.
为什么  雷米
Why is that, Remy?
你干了什么违法的事吗
You been breaking some laws?
如果我擅长干违法的事
If I was any good at law-breaking,
我还会在这里吃老鼠吗
would I be eating a rat?
萝卜白菜  各有所爱
To each their own.
港务长说你可能会顺道过来
Harbormaster said you might be stopping by.
跟那个死掉的科学家有关
Something to do with that scientist who died.
行驶日志上写着那一晚除了霍兰
Logbook says that there was only one other boat
只有另外一艘船开出去了
besides Holland's that went out that night.
而你想知道我看见了什么
And you want to know what I saw?
你是那晚唯一一个当班的人
You were the only person on duty that night.
没错
Yeah.
太他妈奇怪了
Damn strange.
船开出去  过了二十分钟
Boat motors out, 20 minutes later,
炸了
kaboom.
-如果真是谋杀...  -有屁就放  雷米
- If that's a murder... - Spit it the fuck out, Remy.
这么说吧  对你家马特不太有利
Let's just say, it don't look good for your boy Matt.
你个该死的骗子
You're a fucking liar.
有趣的是
Funny thing is,
我觉得你儿子甚至不知道我在那里
I don't think your boy even knew I was there.
办公室关着灯  我又在后面
Office was dark, I was in the back.
但我看见他了
I sure saw him.
他是个高大的年轻人  警长
He's a strapping young man, Sheriff.
还有谁知道这事
Who else knows about this?
暂时没人知道
No one yet.
如果你想保证无人知晓可是要付点代价
It's gonna cost you if you wanna keep it that way.
雷米  雷米
Remy. Remy.
把枪放下
Put the gun down.
别这样  我们可以好好谈谈
Come on, now. We can just talk about this.
要钱是吗
It's about money, right?
行啊  多少
Okay. How much?
五万
50,000.
我想就算是以警察的工资
I figure, even on a cop's salary,
你应该也能凑出这么多
you'll be able to pull that together.
那可能要花点时间
Well, that might take some time,
假设我信你的话
assuming I believe you.
或许你会信他回来后我在船上找到的东西
Maybe you'd believe what I found on that boat when he got back.
炸药的包装纸
Wrapper from some dynamite.
我想桑德兰先生也会愿意出点钱
I figure Mr. Sunderland might wanna chip in, too,
毕竟马特开的是他的船
since it was his boat old Matt was riding around in.
所以你能怎么办就怎么办...
So you do whatever you gotta do--
没人能威胁到我儿子
Nobody ever fucking threatens my son.
有尸体  开枪了
10-45, shots fired.
我需要一个小队来雷米·德博阿的住址
I need a team at the residence of Remy Dubois.
还需要一个验尸官
I'm gonna need a coroner out here, too.
你跟玛丽亚说了什么
What did you tell Maria?
她苦不堪言
Her pain was overwhelming.
她永远放不下肖娜的死
She could never let Shawna's death go.
我做了她要求的事  尽管知道这是错的
I did what was asked of me, even though I knew it was wrong.
你不会真的相信自己让肖娜死而复生了吧
You don't actually think you brought Shawna back from the dead?
我可能打开了一扇门
I may have opened a door,
但我觉得就算肖娜没有我的帮助也会来的
but I think Shawna would have come even without my help.
不管是什么让苏西产生了这样的行为
Whatever it is that's making Susie behave this way,
我比任何人都了解肖娜
I knew Shawna better than anyone.
好吗  那不是她
Okay? That's not her.
黑暗扭曲了她的精神
Darkness has twisted her spirit.
她在吸取玛丽亚的痛苦
She's feeding off Maria's pain.
我只是想在有人受伤前找到她们
I just want to find them before anyone gets hurt.
你还是很愤怒
You're still angry.
是啊
Yeah.
我不会像八岁时那样了
I'm not eight years old anymore,
任由我妈听从你的建议决定生死
watching my mother live and die by your advice.
不管你现在怎么看我
Whatever you think of me now,
我当时只想帮助艾妮丝
I was only trying to help Anise.
我妈需要真正的帮助
My mom needed real help.
我在等你呢  妈妈
I'm waiting for you, Mother.
我很害怕
I'm afraid.
你不爱我吗
Don't you love me?
你不想和我在一起吗
Don't you wanna be with me?
亲爱的  我当然想
Of course I do, honey.
亚凯恩医生
Dr. Arcane!
苏西  你还好吗
Susie, are you okay?
不  我很害怕
No, I'm scared.
我觉得那个坏女孩让桑德兰夫人着道了
I think the bad girl's got Mrs. Sunderland.
我醒来看见她站在沼泽里
I woke up, and I saw her down by the swamp.
来  来
Come here. Come here.
拿着这个  联系凯博副队长
Take this. Get Lieutenant Cable.
玛丽亚
Maria!
Maria.
玛丽亚
Maria!
玛丽亚  停下
Maria, stop.
玛丽亚  很抱歉我杀了肖娜
Maria, I'm sorry I killed Shawna.
她是我最好的朋友
She was my best friend,
过去的每一天我都在想她
and not a day goes by that I don't think about her,
她是因为我才会死的
and she died because of me,
我很抱歉  我很抱歉
and I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry.
你很抱歉
You're sorry?
你用不着道歉
You shouldn't be sorry.
你应该去死
You should be dead!
玛丽亚
Maria.
Maria!
玛丽亚
坚持住  玛丽亚
Stay with me, Maria.
醒醒  醒醒  玛丽亚
Come on. Come on, Maria.
坚持住  玛丽亚
Stay with me, Maria.
她来这是为了和肖娜在一起
She came out here to be with Shawna.
我从她那夺走的女儿
The daughter that I took from her.
你怎么知道我们在这里
How did you know we were here?
我看到你了
I saw you.
你承受着痛苦
You were in pain.
你看到我了
You saw me?
在桥下的水里
In the water, under the bridge.
不不不  这不可能
No, no, no. That's impossible.
肖娜十四年前就死了
Shawna died 14 years ago.
来吧  比艾  好好享受一次
Come on, Y-Bee! Enjoy yourself for once.
你疯了吗  你为什么这么做
Are you crazy? Why did you do that?
这是史密斯街大桥
Smith Street Bridge.
你知道这意味着什么
You know what that means.
你不是认真的吧
You can't be serious.
不  绝对不行
No, absolutely not!
行的  来吧  我们一定得做
Yes, yes, yes! Come on, we gotta!
-肖娜  -只有我们没跳过了
- Shawna... - We're the only ones who haven't done the jump yet.
肖娜  现在是早上五点半
Shawna, it's 5:30 in the morning.
你妈会杀了我们的
Your mom's gonna kill us.
求你了  比艾
Please, Y-bee!
我们还有两天就毕业了
I mean, we graduate in two damn days!
然后谁知道会怎样
And then, who knows what?
上大学  也许我们再也见不到对方了
College? Maybe we'll never see each other again.
你不非得总是当乖乖女
You don't always have to be such a good girl,
你难道就不想叛逆一回吗
you know, don't you ever wanna be bad
就一下下
just for, like, one second?
来吧  我们一起
Come on, come on. Let's do it!
我说不好  肖娜
I don't know, Shawna.
拜托  比艾
Please, Y-Bee!
来吧
Come on!
你先
You first.
艾比
Abby!
肖娜
Shawna?
Shawna!
肖娜
Shawna?
Shawna.
肖娜
Shawna!
你真讨厌
You suck.
太厉害了
That was amazing.
你应该看看自己的表情
You should see your face.
呵呵  真好笑
Oh, ha-ha, hilarious.
玩开心了  回家去吧
Fun time's over! Let's go home.
或者我们可以享受当下
Or we could just enjoy the moment,
扫兴小姐
Miss Buzzkill.
刚刚是什么
What the hell was that?
-别闹了  -不是
- Give me a break. - No.
我是认真的  比艾
I'm serious, Y-Bee.
肖娜
Shawna?
Shawna!
肖娜
什么东西抓走了她
Something took her.
那天一切发生得太快了
It happened so fast that day.
为什么回到那天
Why that day?
为了把我带来这里
To bring me here.
我想那是一个警告
I think it was a warning.
艾比
Abby!
你在哪里
Where are you?
马特  这边
Matt, over here!
艾比
Abby.
坚持住  桑德兰夫人
Hold on, Mrs. Sunderland.
急救人员马上就到
The paramedics are on their way.
你在打颤
You're shivering.
你整晚都要坐在那里盯着我吗
You're gonna sit there staring at me all night?
我是成年人了  莉兹
I'm a grown-ass man, Liz.
我能照顾好自己
I can watch out for myself.
丹尼尔
Hey, Daniel.
周末的烧烤舞会你会来吗
We're gonna see you at the zydeco barbecue this weekend?
显然每周末都会去
And every weekend after that, apparently.
店里的生意不好吗
Things are not going so well at the shop?
是家音像店
It's a video store.
你觉得生意会兴隆吗
How do you think business is doing?
录像带供不应求
Videotapes are just flying off the shelf.
你的手怎么了
What happened to your hand?
见鬼的烧伤
Burnt the hell out of it.
看起来很严重
That's not good.
莉兹  我问你个事
Hey, Liz, can I ask you something?
再来
Here.
你真的喜欢这里吗
Do you really like it here?
我是说  真的喜欢小镇玛雷吗
I mean, really like it here in small town Marais?
这个问题很宽泛
That's a broad question.
你离开过一次  对吗
You left once, right?
我不喜欢小镇的一点
One thing I don't like about small towns
就是所有人都知根知底
is how everyone knows everyone's business.
抱歉
Sorry.
谢谢  再来点坚果  谢谢
Thank you. And some nuts, thanks.
对  我离开过
Yeah, I left.
在杜兰大学攻读新闻专业
Studied journalism at Tulane,
毕业后搬去了纽约
moved to New York right after graduation.
以为我得到了梦寐以求的工作
Thought I landed the dream job.
一年时间转瞬即逝  某天早上醒来
Fast forward a year, woke up one morning
意识到我大部分时间都在改错别字
realizing I'd spent most of my time fixing typos
从来没真正报道过
and zero time reporting.
老爸心脏病发作那次  我就搬回来了
When Pops had a heart scare, I came back for good.
尽管我想在大报社工作  但我意识到
As much as I wanted a job on a big paper, I realized...
我喜欢这里
I like it here.
我得走了
I gotta go.
-晚安  -晚安
- Have a good night. - Good night.
老爸  明早再见
Pops, I'll see you in the morning.
好的  亲爱的
Okay, puddin'.
该死
Shit.
-搞什么  -莉兹·崔梅恩
- What the hell? - Liz Tremayne?
抱歉  不认识她
Sorry, don't know her.
你别再插手惹人生气的事了
You need to stay out of the pissing-people-off business.
否则呢  埃弗里·桑德兰会不得已亲自动手吗
Or what? Avery Sunderland's gonna have to do his own dirty work?
听着  我们不是闹着玩的
Look, we're not playing around!
该死的
God damn!
告诉埃弗里他得找更好的打手
Tell Avery he needs to get better help.
莉兹  怎么回事
Liz! What's going on?
滚开
Back off.
-这他妈...  -丹尼尔
- What the fuck... - Daniel!
丹尼尔  丹尼尔
Daniel. Daniel!
我觉得你他妈把他杀了  快走
I think you fucking killed him! Come on, let's go.
丹尼尔
Daniel!
玛丽亚在哪儿  我妻子在哪儿
Where's Maria? Where's my wife?
桑德兰先生
Mr. Sunderland.
-是我  -她没事
- Yes. - She's okay.
她死里逃生  不过现在情况稳定了
She had a close call but she's stable.
跟我来  这边走
Follow me. Right this way.
桑德兰  我们得谈谈
Sunderland. We need to talk.
现在不行  伍德罗  我妻子在里面
Not now, Woodrue, my wife's in there.
这事等不了
This can't wait.
桑德兰先生  这边走
Mr. Sunderland, right this way.
什么事
What?
亚凯恩找到的那份样本
The sample that Arcane recovered, it's, uh...
来自活的生物
It's from a living creature.
我们明早再谈这事
We'll talk about this in the morning.
你想让我推进这个项目  对吗
You want to me to push this project forward, hmm?
我需要拿它做活体研究
I need it alive on a table to study.
我们必须找到它
We gotta track it down.
抱歉  请告诉她我马上就过去
I'm sorry, could you just please tell her I'll be right with her.
你最好是对的
You'd better be right.
我要给你一个人的名字
I'm gonna give you a name.
业内最厉害的猎人
Best hunter in the business.
找到它
Find it.